## Curriculum Vitae

#### In term time Address:

Hidden Online

**Out of term time Address:** 

Hidden Online

Mobile:

07496167867

**Email:** 

contact@b-waters.com

**Portfolio Website:** 

b-waters.com

Hi, I am a 20-year-old university student studying Cyber Security at Plymouth University. In the future I aspire to train individuals or companies in Cyber Security, 88% of cyber attacks are due to human error (Stanford, 4th March).

# **Ben Waters**

#### **Education**

## 2022 – Present BSc Cyber Security | Plymouth University

Activities and societies: During the first year I was the course rep for stage 1 Cyber Security this means I was responsible for raising any issues that students were having and to ensure a positive working environment.

I'm currently a placement-year student, so far, we have covered a range of topics from software engineering to cyber security and networks.

## 2020 – 2022 A-levels | Sir John Colfox Academy Sixth Form

Computer Science: B, Business Studies: B, Philosophy and Ethics: C and Core Maths: A

# 2015 – 2020 GCSE's | Sir John Colfox Academy

Computer Science: 8, Food Preparation and nutrition: 8, Mathematics: 7, Business Studies: 6, Geography: 6, Biology: 6, Physics: 6, Chemistry: 5, English Literature: 5, English Language: 5.

# **Experience**

#### 2024 - Present Junior DevSec Ops Analyst | BIT Security

In this role my responsibilities encompass website development as well as the implementation and maintenance of PESA - a comprehensive system dedicated to facilitating DBS (Disclosure and Barring Service) and BPSS (Baseline Personnel Security Standard) screening processes.

#### 2023 – 2024 Bartender | Out Out Ibiza

I recently started working in this bar/club as a bartender, primarily I work upstairs in the club but help downstairs in the bar whenever they are busy and need help. I also do PR whether it's a stall on campus or handing out free shot cards outside. I chose to work here as I enjoy the direct interaction with the customers, engaging them and making their night one to remember.

#### 2022 – 2023 **Customer Assistant | Morrisons**

During this time, I primarily worked in produce, however, would always be helping other departments where possible and so I also worked in home delivery, checkouts, the cafe, fresh and the garden centre. This helped me to develop a range of skills and allowed me to have a better understanding of how the store was run. As a result, I was able to provide better customer service and leave the customer feeling as if I went above and beyond.

## 2019 – 2022 Bar Tender/waiter | The Ropemakers

For my first year working here, I worked as a waiter. Waiting on tables and providing great customer service. From my second year onwards, I worked on the bar, whilst continuing to wait on tables, operating the coffee machine and general cleaning. By the end of my time here, I was running shifts, training new staff, cashing up the tills, closing the pub and changing barrels/operating the cellar.

Throughout my time here I have improved myself and my skills. I have shown initiative through a range of difficult situations from bar fights to structural damage requiring emergency builders and handling them appropriately. I've developed relationships with the regulars and have improved my communication skills.

# **Volunteering and Community support**

I used to be part of my county's youth council, which is a group of young people who are passionate about getting young people's voices heard. We develop campaigns and events to support young people and work closely with decision makers to make Dorset a happier place. I also oversaw my school's effort in 'Make Your Mark' to get their votes on what needs to be done to improve Dorset for them.

# **Skills and projects**

I took part in an advanced virtual Cyber Security course ran by Cyber First. Throughout this two-week course, I gained further knowledge of Cyber security techniques such as: open-source intelligence, digital forensics, penetration testing and encryption, along with lots of useful resources to use. Since then, I have been using Immersive labs, which gives you real world cyber security problems and provides a safe space to exploit vulnerabilities.

So far, I have created projects such as an encrypted instant messaging website using PHP with html and CSS, which allowed me to try out methods of encryption and hashing. This also allowed me to improve my problem-solving skills which is highly important when breaking down how to code the program. I have also worked with clients like Arterne CIC to create applications to their requirements. To view all my projects, visit my portfolio website: b-waters.com

#### References

Geraldine Baker	Clay Bryan Security	Adam Griffis
Landlady of The Ropemakers	Team Lead at BIT Security	Senior Manager of Morrisons
07983 611204	07544 585054	07340 843175